<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-20T13:58:27+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ESA Space Solutions Portugal</title><subtitle>🚀 We support entrepreneurs with innovative ideas to develop their business in space and on Earth.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SPARK 4 TECH Open Call is launched!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/docs/calls/2022/10/04/spark4tech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SPARK 4 TECH Open Call is launched!" /><published>2022-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/docs/calls/2022/10/04/spark4tech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/docs/calls/2022/10/04/spark4tech.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;spark-4-tech-open-call-is-launched&quot;&gt;SPARK 4 TECH Open Call is launched!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ESA Space Solutions Portugal has opened applications for SPARK 4 TECH, a programme that supports Portuguese companies interested in transferring space technology for the benefit of Earth. Applications are open until 4 November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPARK 4 TECH aims to fund technical and economic feasibility studies of the transfer of technology used in space in terrestrial applications, in order to prove the relevance of a technology/know-how from space to another technological field, as well as to reduce the business risk and confirm the market opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each project will receive up to 50.000 euros of funding, corresponding to 50% of the total eligible costs (100.000 euros), during the six months of the feasibility study, and access to other ESA funding opportunities. Portuguese entities, companies operating in the space or non-space sector (including SMEs) and academic and research organisations can apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPARK 4 TECH is an initiative of the European Space Agency (ESA) with the support of the Portuguese Space Agency and ANACOM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information at &lt;a href=&quot;https://space.ipn.pt/esa/esa-technology-broker/&quot;&gt;ESA Technology Broker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Pedro Lacerda</name></author><category term="docs" /><category term="calls" /><summary type="html">SPARK 4 TECH Open Call is launched!</summary></entry></feed>